

## CONTACT



+33 684767409



davidcapelle.professionnel@gmail.com



20 rue Cicéron 33600 Pessac - France



LinkedIn profile



**GitHub repositories** 



Video presentation in 2 minutes

## **SOFT SKILLS**

- Rigour, autonomy
- Spirit of synthesis, analytical skills
- Adaptability

#### HARD SKILLS

- Data analysis (EDA)
- Supervided / non supervised machine learning
- Feature engineering
- AWS architecture
- ETL/ELT data pipelines
- Design & buid works : univers,es datawarehouses, datamarts, datalake

# **TOOLS**

- Languages: Python, Streamlit, Flask,
- Databases: Oracle, DB2, MongoDB
- ETL/ELT tool: ODI, Talend
- BI: SAP BI 4, Webi, Qlik Sense
- **Big Data:** AWS (EC2, S3, Sagemaker)
- Machine Learning: Spark, PySpark
- Test tool: HP-ALM

## **HOBBIES**

- Jazz (fusion, nu jazz)
- Finance trading
- Genealogy of succession

# **David CAPELLE**

# JUNIOR DATA SCIENTIST / BI CONSULTANT

Specialist in Business Intelligence for 10 years and IT professional for 25 years, I wish to work as Junior Data Scientist or Expert BI / Data Analyst, mainly in freelance (but I am open to a standard employment contract), partially remote, partially on-site.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES**

## BI / Data Analyst

Sopra Steria (IT company in France) - from 02/2006 to 10/2020

- Pre-sales, POC preparing, tools benchmarks.
- Customer needs analysis, conducting workshops for customers
- Corrective maintenance (ETL/ELT data pipelines, SAP BI universes and Webi reporting).
- Technical and functional tests, facilitating functional committees.
- Support to development teams.

Customers: french public sector (National Education, military defense, Ministry of Sustainable Development).

## **OTHERS EXPERIENCES**

Data Scientist training - RNCP certification level 7 (master) OpenClassrooms / CentraleSupelec - from 03/2021 to 02/2022

- 2 examples of 8 projets (complete list in experiences repository):
- Anticipating demand for electricity consumption

Exploratory data analysis (EDA), supervised machine learning (regression) to predict Seattle's electricity consumption and CO2 emissions.

## Implementation of a scoring model

Creating a scoring model (classification) with custom metrics for approving/refusing bank loans. Build a dashboard deployed in the cloud.

ML skills: Anaconda, Jupyter, Python (numpy,pandas,seaborn, maplotlib, sklearn, yellowbricks, plotly), PCA, k-means, RandomForest, XGBoost, CNN, SVM, LogisticRegression, TensorFlow, Keras.



Full catalog of professional experiences



<u>Data scientist / analyst professional experiences catalog</u>

## **EDUCATION**

Data Scientist RNCP certification (master's degree) (2021-2022) DRT Netwoks and distributed systems (master's degree) (1997) IUP-MIAGE (master's degree in management computing) (1995) **DEUG in Economy** (associate degree in economy) (1993)